Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name
is Marco. My name is Katherine and as you know
we've had a series going about small talk in
English so today's lesson is a part of that series.
That's right today we're going to listen to two
friends, two girlfriends meeting and they haven't
seen each other for a long time so we're just going
to see how they quickly have a small conversation.
Hey Michelle, is that you? Wow Grace long
time no see. Where have you been? Oh yeah
well you see I got a promotion so I moved
to the new Pudong office last September.
You did. Congratulations. Thanks a lot.
So how are things with you Michelle? Well
same old same old you know nothing much has
changed here. Are you still seeing Chris?
Actually we split up last month. Oh dear. I'm
sorry to hear that but I'm in a really cute
guy last night of a networking party so well
let's just wait and see good for you Michelle.
All right we're back
so now let's take a look
at some of that language
on language takeaway.
So the first word we have here
today Marco is the word promotion.
Grace says well you see I got a promotion
so I moved to the new Pudong office.
That's right so she got a promotion
and a promotion is work related.
That means that you
got a better position.
That's right but you didn't change companies
so in your company you had a job and
you did well in that job and so your
boss gave you a better job in the company.
That's right. That's right. Okay so she got a
promotion that's when they were talking about work and
now they started talking about their personal life
and Grace asked if Michelle is still seeing Chris.
Okay so the verb here is to see
someone to be seeing someone.
We're not actually talking about eyes
and looking. We're talking about dating.
That's right. So if you're seeing Chris it
means you're dating Chris. Okay so that's an
interesting way of describing a relationship
so you say yeah I'm sorry I'm seeing someone.
I can't date you I'm seeing someone else
or you could ask someone are you seeing
anyone right now? That means are you dating
anyone? Do you have a boyfriend basically?
Okay and sadly no they
are not together anymore.
She says actually we
split up last month.
All right so this is
another relationship term
to split up means to
break up or to stop dating.
To stop seeing each other.
So there are two ways of
seeing it as you said to
split up or to break up.
That's right. So unfortunately
they split up or unfortunately
they broke up they are no
longer seeing each other.
That's right. Okay but she
said she had some good news
because she met a really
cute guy at a networking party.
What is networking?
All right so networking is
something that you do
especially in the business world.
You go to events, parties, happy hours
and you meet people. You meet strangers
and you talk about work and you
try to meet as many people as you can.
Okay so it's not really a social party to actually
just go and meet random people. You're trying
to meet people that will be interesting for
your business or maybe to get some other ideas.
It's for a business purpose. That's right
so perhaps in your town you own a small
business and your town has decided to have
a chamber of commerce networking party.
So you can meet other small business owners.
Okay very good. So that's what we have
for language take away. Let's go back and
listen to our dialogue for the second time.
Is that you? Wow Grace. Long time no see. Where have you
been? Oh yeah well you see I got a promotion so I moved to
the new Pudong office last September. You did. Congratulations.
Thanks a lot. So how are things with you Michelle?
Well same old same old you know nothing
much has changed here. Are you still
seeing Chris? No actually we split up last
month. Oh dear. I'm sorry to hear that.
But I'm in a really cute guy
last night of a networking party.
So well let's just wait and
see. Good for you Michelle.
So now let's talk about these small quick but very useful phrases for small talk on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this first phrase is a phrase that you'll hear a lot when people greet each other but
perhaps friends who haven't seen each other in a very long time. We use this phrase. Long time no see.
That's right now you look at it and it may seem like it's incorrect right because you're missing something.
That's right long time no see who no see what what long time. That's right.
But this actually means I haven't seen you in a long time. That's right. So the
phrase is long time no see hey Michelle long time no see how are you. That's the
way that you use it but just take it as a phrase don't try to analyze it much.
So hey Marco long time no see.
That's right okay and well they're talking
and she's like well how are you and she
says well you know same old same old.
All right this is another one it doesn't look right
it looks wrong but we do say this and twice same
old same old and this means nothing has changed
there's nothing there's nothing really new in my life.
Right the same old things in my life
nothing really new or exciting same old.
Exactly so I could say hey Marco
you know how's the job going.
Oh you know same old same old. All right so nothing has changed
to his job he has not gotten a promotion. That's right. So no
Michelle was again describing about the guy that she met at
the networking party and she said well let's just wait and see.
It seems like an incomplete sentence
because let's wait and see what.
All right so let's wait and see what that's the question though you know
what are we waiting to see. Well she's basically saying we don't know
how things will go. But we you know we'll have to wait for the future
to come before we we can make a decision or figure out what's going on.
That's right so for example Marco
word the office and I say how is
that that report coming along is it
you know where the numbers good.
And I can say yeah the numbers seemed all
right but we'll just wait and see. Perhaps
we don't have all the numbers yet so we
have to wait to get the the rest of them.
That's right so you're
just basically saying
I don't know what will
happen in the future.
Let's just hope that it
will be good and let's
see what happens.
Let's just wait and see.
Let's just wait and
see. All right so let's go
back and listen to our
dialogue one last time.
Hey Michelle is that you? Wow Grace long
time no see. Where have you been? Oh yeah
well you see I got a promotion so I moved
to the new put on office last September.
You did congratulations. Thanks a lot so
how are things with you Michelle? Well same
old same old you know nothing much has
changed here. Are you still seeing Chris?
No actually we split up last month. Oh dear
I'm sorry to hear that but I'm in a really cute
guy last night of a networking party so. Well
let's just wait and see good for you Michelle.
Okay so this was another part of our small talk series
as you see very useful and quick little phrases so you
can have a very brief conversation with maybe someone
you haven't seen or a little chit chat at the office.
That's right and these are things that if you remember them you memorize then you can use in almost
any conversation. Also I'm sorry to hear that or good for you. These are really great phrases
that are very very flexible. That's right actually that's a really good one. I'm sorry to hear
that maybe someone gives you a little bit of bad news or something bad happened in their life.
It's very polite in a nice way of saying hey I understand I'm sorry to hear that. That's
right so we hope that you've learned something new in today's lesson if you have any questions
about the phrases or words you've heard please check out our website www.EnglishPod.com and
leave us a question on the community section or in a note we'll be happy to answer them.
Alright guys we'll see you there. Bye. Bye.